The bridge...
（アリーシャ）橋が…
There's no way we can get to Marlind.
（マルトラン）
これではマーリンドへ向かえない
We should send medicine at least!
先生 せめて薬だけでも
（マルトラン）だが この流れでは
船で渡ることも不可能だ
With these currents, we won't be able to get a boat across.
（アリーシャ）くっ…
（マルトラン）アリーシャ？
Alisha!
（アリーシャ）これほどの川だ
どこかに 迂回(うかい)路が
There has to be another way to get across!
That's it!
これだ！
We must reach Marlind posthaste!
一刻も早く マーリンドへ
Edna...
（ライラ）エドナさん
Don't worry about it.
（エドナ）いいのよ 別に
（エドナ）
お兄ちゃんを救うって約束
忘れないで
Just remember that you promised to save my brother.
Of course.
（スレイ）うん もちろん
Sorey...
（ミクリオ）スレイ…
We'll ride upon the wind to follow
Your path leading far off into the distance
The answers we seek won't be easy to find
We set out knowing that from the start
We wander endlessly to leave behind records of our dream
It's worth it if it widens our map of the world
Resound, O song of the wind
Should we forgo sight, the voices of our hearts will push us forward
We aim always ever higher
Carry, O song of the wind
Should we go without hearing, the voices of our hearts will stream forth
Emitting a dazzling radiance
Your azure melody rings true
That's why you want to go to Rolance?
（エドナ）それがローランスに
行こうとする理由？
（スレイ）変かな？
Is that weird?
（エドナ）
別に 雑な理由で驚いただけ
Not really. I'm just surprised your reasons are so frivolous.
（ライラ）
スレイさんにとって―
The Celestial Record is like scripture to Sorey.
「天遺(てんい)見聞録」は
聖典ですから
Supposedly, in Rolance, there are many ruins that used to enshrine dragons as gods.
（スレイ）
ローランスには―
ドラゴンを神として
祭った遺跡が―
数多く
残ってるらしいんだ
Did you get that from the book too?
それも本の受け売り？
Yep. That's why I want to travel the world and see.
うん だから俺は
見て回りたいんだ 世界を
たとえ 無駄足になったとしても
それも俺の目的だから
Even if it ends up being a waste of time,
it'll still progress my goals.
Fine, I'll tag along.
いいわ つきあってあげる
Sorey...
スレイさん
（スレイ）ん？
（ライラ）
スレイさんは これまで―
All this time, you've faced down and purified both hellions and malevolence within the land.
憑魔(ひょうま)化した生き物や
大地の穢(けが)れに立ち向かい―
浄化してきました
（スレイ）うん
Yeah.
I want to ask you one more time.
今一度 お尋ねします
What does purification mean to you?
スレイさんにとって
浄化とは どういうものですか？
どういうもの？
Huh?
浄化がどういうものって…
What does it mean to me?
そんなことも分からないで
導師やってるのね
You're the Shepherd, and you don't even know that?
You'll encounter many different kinds of hellions on your journey.
（ライラ）これからの旅で
いろいろな憑魔と出会うでしょう
その数も大きさも さまざまです
They come in all shapes and sizes.
I know you have the resolve to purify them.
導師として それを浄化する
その覚悟について―
スレイさんにウソは
ありませんでした
I never doubted that about you.
But if you throw yourself at hellions day after day,
ですが ただやみくもに
憑魔と対峙するだけでは―
you yourself might succumb to the malevolence.
いつか穢れに
のみ込まれてしまうかもしれません
でも 俺にはどうすればいいか…
Then what should I do?
What's important is to use your imagination.
想像してみることが 大事ですわ
My imagination?
（スレイ）想像？
（ライラ）はい
Yes.
Imagine this fire is a hellion and try to purify it.
この炎を憑魔だと思って
浄化してみてください
You must understand the malevolence.
穢れを自らが理解する
その穢れに対する
導師としての答え
Only then will you understand what you must do as the Shepherd.
Not even close.
まだまだね
ああ…
なかなかうまくいかないや
This is harder than it looks.
You've never purified a person who has turned into a hellion before.
スレイさんは まだ―
憑魔化した人を
浄化したことはありません
その訓練もしないとですわね
You need training for that too.
Yeah.
He definitely has the potential to become a great Shepherd.
（ライラ）やはり―
スレイさんの導師としての資質は
確かなもの
But he's driven only by a very pure desire to help others, which makes him fragile as well.
しかし それは
困っている人を助けたいという―
純粋な根源ゆえ 壊れやすい
Mikleo...
ミクリオさん
I fear we'll be needing you very soon.
あなたが必要になるのは
そう 先のことではなさそうです
（アタック）ひゃあああ～！
No!
あっ あかんわ あかんて～
Spare me!
A Normin seraph?
ノルミン天族？
Normin Power!
パワー･ガ･ノルミーン！
ハァ… フゥ… フゥ…
（ミクリオ）い… 今のは君が？
D-Did you do that just now?
ハァッ せ せや～ うう…
Y-Yeah...
Man, I'm pooped.
あ～ しんど～
（アタック）んん んん んん…
プッハハハハー！
生き返ったわ～
That really hit the spot!
So... Mikleo, was it?
ええっと ミクリオはんでしたな
You really saved my butt back there!
あんたのおかげで助かりましたわ
Y-Yeah...
You're a Normin?
君は ノルミン天族だよね？
That's right.
おっしゃるとおり
うちは ノルミン天族の
アタックいいますねん
I'm Atakk. Nice to meet you.
よろしゅうに
I'm surprised you know about us, considering how young you are.
ミクリオはんは
お若い天族みたいやのに―
よお知ってまんなあ
My foster parent told me.
（ミクリオ）
僕の育ての親から聞いたんだ
昔はノルミン天族が
各地に存在していたおかげで―
I heard that in the past, humans and seraphim were able to get along better because of the Normin.
人間と天族の関係も
より良好だったって
えっへん うちらノルミン天族は
力は弱いけどなあ―
That's right! We Normin may be weak on our own,
他の天族はんの力を
ええ感じに強める能力があるんや
but we have the ability to boost the power of other seraphim!
Yeah, you really surprised me earlier.
ああ さっきは驚いた
But that didn't purify the hellion.
だけど あれで
憑魔が浄化されたわけじゃない
アタック
Atakk...
If you live in this forest,
you should leave while you can.
この森が住みかなら
離れたほうがいいと思う
（アタック）潮時… なんやろな
I guess it's time.
What about you? Where are you going?
ミクリオはんは
これからどちらへ？
I...
（ミクリオ）僕は―
あの雲のふもとへ行こうと思ってる
I plan to go to the base of that cloud.
あれは普通の雲じゃない
That's no ordinary cloud.
I've got a bad feeling about it.
何か起きてるんじゃないかって
気になるんだ
It's been there for a few days now.
確かに 何日か前からありますなあ
But what're you gonna do when you get there?
けど あんなとこ行って
何しはるん？
友達を見つけなきゃいけない
I must find my friend.
はあ… 友達
Friend?
フフッ 決めた！
I know!
Until I find a new home, I'll follow you!
次の住みかが見つかるまで
うちも一緒に行くわ
あんたとうちが力を合わせれば―
If we join forces, we can beat the hellions like we did back there!
憑魔もさっきみたいに
やっつけられるし
What do you say?
どやろか？
Sure, I don't mind.
ああ かまわない
Pleased to have you, Atakk.
よろしく アタック
あれ？
Huh?
（兵士１）導師様
アリーシャ様より言づてです
Shepherd Sorey! Princess Alisha has an urgent message for you!
グリフレット橋が…
Griflet Bridge has been...
The bridge?
橋？
じゃあ 借りていくね
（兵士１）お気をつけて
Thanks for the horse.
Please be careful.
Alisha...
（スレイ）アリーシャ
（アリーシャ）やんだ？
It stopped raining?
What the...
一体… あっ！
ただの嵐ではないということか
This is no ordinary storm.
みんな 詮索は後回しだ
We can investigate this later!
We have to focus on delivering this medicine!
今は薬を届けることだけを考えよう
Princess!
（兵士）姫様
Let's go.
行こう
We must first deliver the medicine to Marlind.
（マルトラン）
まずはマーリンドへ薬を届ける
We can worry about moving the troops after the weather's cleared up.
隊を動かすのは
天候が回復してからでいい
あとの指揮は… ん？
For further orders...
What's going on?
何だ？
何だ？ この雨
What is this rain?!
（ライラ）スレイさん 上を
Sorey, look up!
A hellion?!
憑魔！
（マルトラン）うっ…
（スレイ）みんな ケガはない？
Is everyone okay?!
Shepherd?!
（マルトラン）導師！
Stand back. It's dangerous.
危ないから離れてて
What's an Oroboros doing here?!
ウロボロスが こんな場所に
ウロボロス？
Oroboros?
A powerful hellion.
（ライラ）強力な憑魔です
This storm must be his doing.
この嵐も そのせいでしょう
I'll protect these people.
私は あの方々を守ります
All right!
（スレイ）分かった
エドナ！
Edna!
I guess I should show off my Sub Lord powers.
私も陪神(ばいしん)たるところを
見せておかないとね
Let's go!
よし！ ハクディム＝ユーバ！
Hephsin Yulind!
ぐっ！ ふああ！
（スレイ）うう… ぐう！
でやあ！
You seem to be able to use my powers well enough.
（エドナ）
力は ちゃんと使えてるみたいね
ああ このまま一気に決めよう
Yeah! Let's finish this quick!
な… 何だ？
What?!
ドラゴン！
A dragon?!
No, that's a drake.
（エドナ）
違う あれはドラゴンパピー
A drake?
パピー？
（エドナ）
ドラゴンになる前の幼体のことよ
A younger hellion, not yet fully a dragon.
If it's still a drake, it can be purified! Sorey!
パピーなら まだ浄化は可能です
スレイさん！
（スレイ）ふっ！ ぐおお！
う… ぐわあ！
（エドナ）あんなに高く飛ばれたら
浄化しようがないわ
We can't purify it if we can't get to it.
Damn!
（スレイ）クソッ
（マルトラン）
また君に助けられたな
You saved us yet again.
（スレイ）
マルトランさん アリーシャは？
Lady Maltran...
Where is Alisha?
Alisha is taking a different road to Marlind.
（マルトラン）アリーシャなら
別の道からマーリンドへと向かった
I hope she's safe.
無事ならいいが
The drake was heading for Marlind.
マーリンドはドラゴンパピーが
飛び去った方角ですわ
Hey, Edna, maybe you can use your power to...
（スレイ）
あのさ エドナの力があれば…
ムチャ言わないで
もう力は残ってないわ
Don't be ridiculous. I don't have any strength left.
でも 流れが落ち着けば
何とかできるかもね
But...
If the current slows down, I might be able to do something.
No kidding? You know Lailah?
（アタック）何や
ミクリオはんは ライラはんの
お知り合いやったんか
What a coincidence.
奇遇やなあ
You know Lailah?
ライラを知ってるのか？
ヘヘッ 実はうち―
Lailah and I have a bit of, uh, history together.
ライラはんとは
ちょいとワケありなんよ
History?
（ミクリオ）ワケあり？
（アタック）フンッ それは
いくらミクリオはんでも言えんよ
Well, I can't really talk about it.
Not even with you.
It's a sensitive man-woman kind of thing.
男女のデリケートな
お話やからね～
デリケートね…
Sensitive, huh?
Whoa, what a huge river!
（アタック）うわあ でっかい川や
We'll never get across this.
これは渡んのは無理やなあ
Mikleo...
ミクリオはん
（ミクリオ）ん？
Look at that.
（アタック）
ちょっと あれ見てえや
What happened?
Is that...
これは…！
Yes, it was like this since this morning.
（兵士）
ええ 今朝の時点ですでに…
やはり これは―
This can only be the Shepherd's doing.
導師の成せる業としか
考えられぬか
What?!
導師！
（兵士）導師様の？
The Shepherd?
He must've created those rocks to get across.
（マルトラン）あの岩場を作り出し
川を渡っていったのだろう
Yeah, a human definitely didn't make that.
んっ 確かに
人が作ったもんやないなあ
（ミクリオ）
スレイ… ここまでの力を
Sorey... Is this how strong you've become?
Well, let's get going.
（スレイ）あ…
（アタック）さあ 行こ
ミクリオはん
Your friend is waiting, right?
お友達が待ってるかもしれんのやろ
Yeah.
This is Marlind, the second largest city in Hyland?
（スレイ）ここが
ハイランド第２の街 マーリンド
ひどいわね
It's a mess.
The whole town is tainted with malevolence, almost as bad as my brother's domain.
街全体が お兄ちゃんの領域と
同じくらいの穢れだわ
（ライラ）スレイさん…
Sorey...
This plague is definitely caused by that drake.
（スレイ）
この疫病の原因は間違いない
あのパピーだ
大丈夫だよ 薬が効いてくれば
すぐよくなるから
Don't worry.
You'll feel better once the medicine kicks in.
Alisha!
（スレイ）アリーシャ
（アリーシャ）ん？
スレイ 来てくれたのか？
Sorey! You came!
ふうん この子がアリーシャ？
So this is Alisha?
Who was that?
（アリーシャ）今の お声は？
ああ エドナっていって
新しく仲間に…
Oh, that's Edna. She's a new...
あっ… って 声が聞こえるの？
まだ手を取ってないのに
You can hear her? We're not even holding hands!
Oh, you're right.
そう言えば…
（ライラ）きっと スレイさんの
霊応力(れいのうりょく)が高まったのでしょう
Sorey's resonance must've improved.
Now people can hear the seraphim just by standing near Sorey.
それで
スレイさんの近くにいるだけで―
天族の声が
聞こえるようになったのですわ
（アリーシャ）あ… ライラ様
Lailah!
Yes!
（ライラ）はい アリーシャさん
ご無事で何よりです
Alisha, I'm glad you're well.
Yeah, I was worried.
うん よかった 心配してたんだ
スレイ
Sorey...
I...
私は…
Alisha!
（スレイ）あっ アリーシャ
I can't take this anymore.
（アリーシャ）もう ダメなんだ
The medicine I brought isn't working.
運んできた薬が 効かなかった
No one's getting better.
誰１人として回復に向かわない
このままでは―
At this rate...
Everyone will...
みんなが…
分かってる
I know.
えっ？
（スレイ）原因を何とかしないと
I must get to the source.
あいつだ
It's him!
There's a hellion here?!
（アリーシャ）いるのか？ 憑魔が
いる
Yeah.
アリーシャ この方向に何かある？
Alisha, what's over there?
There's a hill.
高台があって―
And a sacred tree known as the Great Tree.
そこに 聖なる大樹と呼ばれる
ご神木が…
（エドナ）
あいつ それに巣くう気ね
It's making its nest there.
エドナ 今度は
飛んで逃げられないように―
Edna, is there a way to stop it from flying away again?
あいつの動きを封じられないかな？
Let me try.
やってみるわ
よし！
All right!
な… うわあ！
（エドナ）ウソ！
No way!
（エドナ）前よりも力が上がってる
It's more powerful than last time.
あいつ ドラゴンになる寸前よ
It's on the verge of becoming an actual dragon!
If that happens, then Marlind will...
（ライラ）
そうなったらマーリンドは…
させるか！
I won't let it!
うっ… 何だ？ この穢れは
What is this malevolence?
うわああああ！
あれは ドラゴンパピーや
It's a drake!
（ミクリオ）
スレイたちが戦っているんだ
Sorey must be fighting it!
（アタック）憑魔や！
（ミクリオ）アタック 頼む！
It's a hellion!
Atakk, help me!
（咆哮）
（アタック）パワー･ガ･ノルミン！
Normin Power!
We did it!
やったー！
（ミクリオ）ああっ！
いやああ！
ぐう…
If Mikleo was here...
（ライラ）
ミクリオさんが いてくれたら…
Lailah!
ライラ
Mikleo went to retrieve an armatus that's a bow.
（ライラ）ミクリオさんが
取りに行った神器は 弓なんですの
それがあれば…
If only we had that...
（スレイ）ミクリオなら 来るよ
Mikleo will come.
Huh?
He's close. I just feel it.
（スレイ）
ミクリオが近くまで来てる
そんな気がするんだ
So just hold out a little longer!
だから…
もう少しだけ 踏ん張ってくれ
でやあ！
ライラ！
Lailah!
（スレイ）ぐうう… うっ！
Sorey!
スレイさん！
スレイ！
（アタック）ライラはーん！
Sorey!
Lailah!
ミクリオ！
Mikleo!
えっ ア… アタックさん？
A-Atakk?
何？ あの子が？
What? That kid?
Mikleo, quick! The Sub Lord pact!
ミクリオさん 早く！
私と陪神契約を！
（ミクリオ）ライラ 頼む！
Do it, Lailah!
O ye born of the sacred currents of peace...
（ライラ）
静謐(せいひつ)なる流れに連なり生まれし者よ
Here let our pact be forged, that my unquavering incandescence may be as thy purification.
今 契りを交わし
我が煌々(こうこう)たる猛(たけ)り―
清浄へ至る輝きの一助とならん
汝(なんじ) 承諾の意思あらば
その名を告げるのは省略！
Shouldst thou accept this burden, recite aloud your... Et cetera!
Mikleo! Give Sorey your true name!
さあ 真の名をスレイさんに！
He already knows!
そんなのとっくに…
You bet I do!
知ってるって！
ルズローシヴ＝レレイ！
Luzrov Rulay!
Let's do it, Mikleo!
行くぞ ミクリオ
Right!
ありったけの力を込める
I'll give it everything I've got!
（ミクリオ･スレイ）
全てを貫け 蒼穹(そうきゅう)の十二連
Break on through!
Azure Assault!
（スレイ･ミクリオ）
あ… ハァ… ハァ…
ハァ… ハァ… ハァ…
If we close our eyes now,
here on this journey with no turning back,
we can find our moments of peace
and make our wishes as we sleep
I dreamed of the world
and the hope and warmth
that our devotion can give to it
We can stop and rest
for the morrow
and together
we can laugh
I'm sure we can fulfill our duties
at the end
of this long journey
For now, let us sleep
and dream of the future
Let us walk together
Next Time
Mikleo, are you hurt?
Sorey
I'm okay. You have a scratch on your hand, though.
Mikleo
This is nothing.
Sorey
I bet you missed me.
Mikleo
Speak for yourself.
Sorey
I was fine.
Mikleo
Just admit it, Mikleo.
Sorey
What are you two bickering about?
Mikleo
Edna?
Sorey
Mikleo, meet Edna, an earth seraph.
Nice to meet you. I'm Mikleo, a water seraph.
Mikleo
Hey there, water boy.
Edna
Mikleo, not "water boy."
Mikleo
Mikleo Notwaterboy? That's a new one.
I'll call you Meebo for short.
Edna
It's Mikleo, all right?! Mikleo!
Mikleo
Now, now, you two. Why don't you stop there before it drags on?
Lailah
Sorey, I think it's time for next week's preview.
Next time, "Alisha Diphda."
Sorey
Sorey, did you call?
Alisha